All right, welcome back to another
episode of the operators pod. I got
Curtis and Mike with me today. We got a
three topics we're going to dig into.
The first is a longstanding debate in
consumer. It is owned warehouse versus
3PL. 3PL, how do you pick them? How do
you price them? How do you compare these
things? Uh we're going to just jam on
this for a little bit about like how we
have experienced this topic, right?
Curtis, you're super deep in it. Mike,
you've got both. I've done both. Uh, and
with all of this wrapped up in Amazon's
now opening up their entire logistics
network as like an AWS for for
logistics. So, I think it's time that we
just hit this. Um, and I think I'd like
to start it off, guys, with
let's start broad. Let's start with is
there a scenario in which owning your
own warehouse is the right call? Like
you handle your own fulfillment. Mike,
how do you think about this? And Curtis,
I'll get your your read on this second,
but Mike, kick us off, man. Where would
you then own your own freaking
infrastructure?
>> Yeah, I think if we're going to talk
about this, first thing I'd just say is
it's just like owning your own
manufacturing. There's situations where
like it makes sense to own your own uh
fulfillment and to vertically integrate
there. And there's situations where it
doesn't. And uh not surprisingly
actually a lot of the same principles
that apply to manufacturing I think
apply here. So we there were a number of
kind of posts on social media going back
and forth about this idea and uh our
friend Bill uh put together a really
good one where he basically was making
the argument that it's it's kind of a
siren song like doing your own
fulfillment a siren song that can
actually slow slow down your growth and
ecom.
So, I guess I'll start here by saying
like the reason I think that fulfillment
feels attractive is that it's not
complicated. So, you're paying somebody
when you're paying somebody else to do
it, you're looking at you're like
nothing about what you're doing is
complicated. I could do it and then I
could make more money. And there's a lot
of good reasons. I mean, there's a
reason why so many people rely on 3PL's
that doing the 3PL work is actually a
lot more complicated than people think
it is. And just like manufacturing the
uh you need kind of economies of scale
and if you don't have economies of scale
then it doesn't really work. So like
just really simply one of the things
we've learned is hey you have to step
into a lease if you're going to do your
own fulfillment and that means that
you're paying a certain amount every
month regardless of how much you use the
facility. So all of a sudden like hey
that you have to have a certain amount
of volume, a certain amount of storage,
a certain amount of throughput on
fulfillment or like this isn't going to
make any sense at all. And I think the
generalized advice uh is like hey if
you're a brand and you're growing
quickly like the primary concern when it
comes to fulfillment is to just have
somebody that can keep up with you and
can be flexible with you. So, like we
worked with a local partner, Encore, and
uh even though we probably have given
them a bunch of gray hair, they were an
incredibly good partner in that what we
really needed more than anything else
was not cost savings early on. It was
like flexibility. Like we could tell
them, hey, we think we need 60,000
square feet and then we come back a
month later sheepishly and we're like,
well, we need 120,000 square feet, you
know, or or vice versa.
as we have grown and matured as a
company now I think I'm starting to like
we are building a building we are going
to be doing more of a fulfillment and
we're at a different stage and I'd be
happy to talk about like why that's true
but I think the generalized advice to
start with is like it's really great to
have a good partner here early on and
when you're in the growth phase and then
as your business matures I think
everybody develops this kind of urge to
think about vertical integration and how
can I do more and I'd be happy to talk
about how we've done So initial variable
here to think about for people is higher
growth rate. 3PL is likely a better
option. They are more set up to handle
capacity increases, right? Um and the
the I guess Curtis, you've hit on this
in the previous episode, like you you
buy a building or you set up a building
uh and you quickly outgrow it and now
all of a sudden it's like physical space
and your own logistics is a constraint.
Whereas once you're bigger, it's slower,
right? So you can do it. So Curtis, take
us away. Like give us give us your take
on this.
>> I'm in Portland and I'm in a 24,000 foot
building that I bought. Now when I
started this company, it was just in a
little room, 2,000 foot. Then we
expanded out. Okay. We have now
officially bought and sold racking in
the basement of this thing four
different times. We need more racking.
We buy this expensive racking. You put
it down into the cement. You get OSHA
approved. and then we change something
and they sell the racking off for 30
cents on the dollar and then I'm out and
they do it again and then they do it
again. In your growing you don't know
how much you need. So if you're doubling
every year, I love to tell this story.
Every year you're doing in one year what
you did in the entire history of a
company.
>> So if you do 1 million, then 2 million,
then four million, the next year you're
doing eight, you've done more than
you've done in the entire history. The
next year you do to 16. You've done more
than the entire history of your company.
So every year you're doing that. The
first thought if you want to set up your
own warehousing is, "Oh, we need to get
it space." Great. Sign a lease. Let's
sign a 5-year lease. How much space do
you need? I have no idea. I have zero.
Can you give me this amount with the
ability to grow 10x if I need it? Well,
no one's signing that damn lease. So,
you think you're going to do it in
house? We went to a 3PL that could grow
and I'm gonna tell you what, they
sucked. They really really sucked. But
it it got us the ability to take our
best people on manufacturing, on new
product design, on marketing, on a lot
of the other things while they are
sucking at the 3PL. Then we move to a
second. Now we're at a third one. And
I'm going to tell you what's happened in
that time is their efficiency has got
better, their price has got better.
We've gotten better with working with
them. And I love vertical integration.
I'm a control freak. I want to control
everything. I don't want a big, you
know, 400,000 foot warehouse.
Everywhere we turn right now, there is
some worldchanging AI announcement. And
I think the trick for us operators is
figuring out what's actually going to
help our business. Is this stuff saving
us money? Is it helping us grow revenue?
Is it helping us grow profit? Like,
where is the freaking ROI? Jason for
Hexclad, tell everybody what is actually
working for you guys. Yeah, look, I'm
laser like focused on implementing AI
wherever we can to just make us more
efficient. Fulfill has been huge for us.
Like my team is constantly using
Fulfill's new CLI tool and MCP features
with Claude. They're now able to query
fulfilled data. They they can v code up
dashboards. Um, I mean, we get these
awesome dashboards on operations and and
Fulfill continues to build things that
are actually useful for brands. It's
hard to see what kind of AI work is
valuable and what isn't. Sure. Like
there's so much out there, so much
coming at us, but Fulfill seems to be
giving us things we can really use to
get more efficient.
So, Curtis, you you don't have you don't
do your own direct to consumer shipping.
So you're vertical in manufacturing, but
then you use a 3PL to handle
fulfillment. I think that's important.
Is it fair to say, Mike, that the
dollars saved, so like the allure, this
the siren song is that like if I have my
own warehouse, I save X dollars per
package, I get my own rate, blah blah
blah. Is it fair to say that the that
siren song that allure is offset by the
brain damage what Curtis is talking
about which is like the focus of some of
your best people are now going to be on
how do you be a great fulfillment center
instead of putting it into product or
into marketing or into something else
that is actually I guess like further up
the value stack. I have come to think of
business as it's primarily an order of
operations
exercise. You know like when you learn
with math that like okay first you do
the multiplication and then you do this
and then you do the addition that like
most of the kind of generalized takes
that people have are right but if you
get them in the wrong order then it can
be wrong for your business. And so a
part of being an effective operator is
not just identifying what are all the
opportunities in your business. So you
might look at your business and say,
"Hey, I see these six opportunities for
growth on the bottom line." But the hard
part that takes judgment is to then say,
"Okay, and what's the sequence?" And to
have the discipline to say, "I see that
I see that way to produce more profit,
but not yet." And I think the thing that
typically makes great entrepreneurs
great is bias to action. And so
restraint and discipline when it comes
to the order that you're going to attack
things is something that we're not very
good at and it pulls against our
strengths. So that when you see an
opportunity in your business, I think
the first question is just like is that
a real opportunity? And then I think the
second question is is now the right
time? uh because I think the way that we
tend to approach problems as
entrepreneurs is like question one is
there that a real opportunity and then
step two is do it and that's that's
really actually not the most effective
way to handle it especially as your
business gets bigger Curtis made this
analogy and I think it's a really good
one about space and how could you
possibly know if your brand is growing
at 30 or 40% how much space you're going
to need in five years like you just have
to guess at an unknown knowable future.
And it reminds me of we we first when we
first started the company, we had no
money and so we had no office. We we met
in the upstairs of my house and and like
Panera and stuff. And then we finally
got an office. It was like,00 square
feet. It was basically one big common
area and it was kind of chaotic. And
eventually we got enough people where we
were like I think a year into that lease
where we had to move. And I remember
when we got the the initial lease, like
my the guy who negotiated it on our
team, he was like, "Do we feel good
about signing a five-year lease?" And I
was like, "Well, you know, like if we're
getting so big that we've outgrown it,
then that's a good problem to have." And
so then we moved from there to another
building and we got into another lease.
And guess how long it took us to outgrow
that lease? A year. And so we get into
the third building and we sign a lease
and two months into that lease, COVID
hits. And so we're now working remote. I
have three leases on three different
buildings and we're using none of them.
And what what the process taught me is I
was like, "Okay, from now on I'm going
to have one lease on one building." But
it was just like an illustration of it's
very very difficult to understand the
amount of physical space your business
is going to need at different stages in
its life cycle. And you really shouldn't
be trying to guess at that until you're
in a more mature kind of stage, a more
mature growth curve. So with Simple
Modern, I'm 11 years in almost, and it's
a lot easier for me to have some concept
of what our physical space might needs
might be a year or three years from now.
But it would it was a total fool's
errand in the first five years of the
company. And we made tons of mistakes as
a result of that
>> and you wind up in in sub lease uh
situations. So like now now not only do
you have multiple leases, but you're
probably trying to sub it out to
somebody else. So you're you've turned
into like a sub landlord. We're in this
beautiful building and ironically the
way that I got into it was subleasasing
it from somebody else who had moved out
and was just paying rent on a building
they weren't even using and I ended up
buying the building at like half of its
market value during COVID. But like one
of the best investments of my life was
actually somebody else making the same
mistake that you're talking about.
>> It's um you know Curtis the you and I
the thing that we share is that we're
both vertically integrated on the
manufacturing side. I think the
difference between us though is my end
product is quite small and because we
make everything on demand, we actually
do the last mile fulfillment like we
just manufacture and ship out of the
same building because it doesn't take up
a lot of space and it's actually the
probably the easiest step in the entire
process of making the thing and shipping
the thing is just putting in a box and
shipping the thing. So we've we have no
3PL's anymore now. we used to except
we were one of those people that the uh
3PL's did not want and a part of that
was skew variation and apparel companies
I think in particular are a good example
of like sometimes an apparel company
does need to run its own fulfillment
simply because the skew variation is so
freaking insane, right? like they have
thousands and thousands and thousands of
actual skew variations which means the
bins required are high and you get dep
prioritized as a as a client to these
3PLs.
I am curious as Portland Leather like as
you guys have leaned more into 3PL's
like how have you handled this because
you guys have a lot of SKs like how how
do the 3PL's deal with you?
Implementing AI without trusted data is
shooting in the dark and building
application from scratch. Dealing with
Tableau, dealing with data pipelines,
dealing with all that, it doesn't have
to be your headache. You can hire Saras
analytics to handle that stuff for you.
Saras IQ gives your leadership team a
single shared view of the truth.
Contribution margin, channel
performance, customer economics, all can
be answered instantly with the power of
Saras analytics. Do not fall behind.
Saras Analytics is experts. They've set
it up for Ridge, Hexcloud, hundreds of
other brands. Speak to them today.
Connect whatever AI tool you already
use, and you can put that right on top
of your personal data privately,
securely, and you can start talking to
your data like your favorite chatbot.
First of all, let's explain that 3PL's
want everybody to be really easy and to
pay them way too much money, right? They
just like come in and they'll complain
about any work they actually have to do.
So that's like something to always keep
in mind. We just got
when we did everything ourselves. Um it
was a lot of work, but we really were
good at what we did. And when the 3PL
came in, they mocked us. They basically
were like, "Well, let let's explain how
we're doing it, how we care about our
customers, and like, oh, this is a
science. We're experts. We don't need to
listen to We got this. We got this."
They didn't have it, right? They were
just trying to sell us and they showed
us a big warehouse and we said yes. I
think that any 3PL you need to work with
and have people on the ground in their
3PL every single month. We currently
have a big transition. We have two
employees, full-time employees there on
site for the first six months.
>> Yeah. just to make sure they're doing
things the right way because one
screw-up can be really big. And uh they
have different priorities. These are
huge companies and they'll send the
priority down. And sometimes I say, "I
want these 10,000 products found, put
through the system before anything
else." We just recently did that. And
they're like, "Oh, we'll get to it." And
I'm like, "No, not get to it. I want
them today." Okay. And I made them go
out with a cell phone with a yellow
piece of paper, go find what I wanted
and show me on a video that they're
putting it on the right pallets. And
then I say, "I want the name. Show me a
video of the guy waving at me with the
cart taking it and putting it into what
I need to have." Right? And they thought
that was funny and they did it. And all
of a sudden, we filled up on Shopify.
Our sales went up. We did 200,000 more
because I made them do that. They had
waited a long time. These are not bad
people. They're good people. They're in
very, very, very big systems. I think
learning how to do a 3PL like you're
doing, Matt, when you start, like Mike
did when he started, and then after you
get better coming back to it, I would
love to in a couple years go back to
owning my own and taking some of that
money that they're taking from me, but
right now my growth in other areas is
just worth too much,
>> you know? So, so Mike, you you mentioned
this complicated thing because I think
what Curtis is saying is like it's just
the complexity of it is not worth it to
him right now. What are other areas like
when you think running your own
fulfillment? I mean, we're not talking
about like I don't run a 3PL for other
brands, right? And I don't think Mike,
you're going to either. It's like this
is just you're owning fulfillment for
your own brands. What about it? Like
what what complications are top of mind
for you when you think about this? like
where is the brain damage for people
considering it? One thing that is pretty
obvious but is is definitely a drain is
you just attract a different type of
person and with those type of jobs and
it just it just has to be said and it's
like you're not you're not managing
white collar workers and there are some
great people that work in 3PL's but they
do tend to have different lifestyles.
They do tend to stay in jobs shorter
periods of time and and you do tend to
have, you know, problems like we've
we've had caught people doing drugs in
the bathroom and had to let them go. You
know, we we had like when you get your
So, we we've been talking about the
space planning. Well, not only do you
have to like plan out the space for what
you think you'll need, you plan out your
personnel. And so when you're wrong, you
don't just have a space problem, but you
also have a personnel problem. And that
means you're going into temp workers.
And I think
working with temp workers is quite
challenging. So like there was a period
where we had to use temp workers for a
while and we found one of them had
stolen like a thousand water bottles and
had filled the their garage with water
bottles uh by the time we caught them.
and and like you know like I'm not this
is nothing against temp workers right
it's honest work and needs to be done
but just you're going to get a much
higher variance and a a much bigger
spectrum of the types of people that
you're managing and and quite frankly
most white collar people don't want to
manage that and and it's just headaches
you know it's just like it's just
complexity and liability that when
you're growing a brand you're like hey I
want to sell more, you know, purses. I
don't want to like worry about
somebody's background check just came
back and they they flunked their
background check and we haven't been
able to fill this position because
people keep flunking background checks.
And so anyway, like that piece has to be
said. Now, with that said, I do think
this is an area that's going to get
fairly revolutionized because
um and and I just want to reiterate, we
have a great team. I really love the
people in our facility, but it's it is
more challenging. But like one of the
ways that this is going to be
revolutionized is the robotics thing is
going to is already coming for 3PL's but
like this is just the beginning you know
like Optimus robots and all this stuff
like you look at some of the the videos
of what's possible and I think that just
like customer support is one of the most
obviously disrupted jobs uh via AI uh I
think the most obviously disrupted job
via robotics is 3PL s and you know
having one of the worst things is like
having shipments that go out to the
wrong address or have the wrong stuff
packed in them or whatever. These are
like economically pretty devastating
when mistakes happen and like machines
are just not going to make the same
errors and they can work whenever and
hit whatever shipment deadline and they
don't have overtime and they don't have
benefits. And so I I think that this
this is one thing that's going to tip
things in some ways that if you have the
capital to invest in robotics,
I think it's going to be more
interesting and compelling to run a 3PL
than it is maybe today. But the the
people side of it cannot be
underestimated. And I think that this is
a more generalized take on business that
you think being successful in business
is mostly about having a good strategy
and executing on it. and you just don't
think about how much business is really
just about managing people and that
that's really the job.
>> You know, Curtis, the uh you mentioned
what what Mike's making me think of here
is uh three pe like running a warehouse.
There's a lot of difficulties with it.
You've you've said that uh you know, you
pay these companies a lot of money,
right? So like there's definitely an
that's the attraction. It's like maybe
I'll do this at a certain scale and my
growth rate will slow down. It'll make
sense to run it myself. How do you then
so let's let's just look at like as you
are today. How are you evaluating which
3PL's you choose? Uh is it purely price
driven? Are there other things that you
look for when you've made these choices
in the past? Like you've got a lot of
reps here.
>> Yeah. But first of all, let's just say
how different it is. Mike and Portland
Leather because because I'm in our
Portland Leather. He said they catch
people doing drugs in the bathroom and
they let them go. Here we have to give
them a promotion and talk to HR
>> in Portland. In Portland, you get in
trouble for interrupting them for using
drugs. [laughter]
>> Exactly. I get in trouble. Would you
please give them a few more minutes so
they can complete the task? So, that's a
little bit different right there. I'm
gonna tell you, we really try to work
with 3PL's
and the last move we made uh was a
company from called Cart.com who were
very nice people and they really tried
and we went to a biggie. We went to
flexport
and the reason we did it is the
technology was better or promised to be
better and our people thought that it
did and they saved us just a load of
money. They like literally guaranteed
23% savings. And when you're spending
tens of millions of dollars a year,
that's a lot. And they gave us a $2
million bonus for transferring over to
Flex.
And so when here's the key. When I said
this to Cart, they said, "Oh, we'll
match that." And I said, "You son of a
have been making that much on
us. Now I'm so pissed. I'll never stay
with you anyhow."
Right? We kept waiting for the
efficiencies to catch on our last 3PL
and for the pricing to go down and we
kept promising that that was going to
happen.
Uh
and it just never actually
came through. Well, okay. So, go back
though. Like why did you choose them in
the first place? Like I guess every time
I talk to somebody, just to frame this
up, uh this is this is the most
requested referral I get. I don't know
about you guys, but like in our network
when somebody is I get a message about,
hey, do you have a referral? Like I need
a a referral to somebody. I'm like,
what's it for? It's 3PL. It's the number
one thing I get asked about. So Curtis,
how are you choosing like how did you
choose the if you look at like your
history with each 3PL? Is it just cost?
Is that always the like number one thing
or are there other criteria that you're
also looking at? Le
>> let's admit that as an entrepreneur I
can be very stupid sometimes. Okay,
let's just all jump. We We
>> We were all good with saying that.
>> We like to sound smart on here because
Mike's been doing this 11 years. I've
been doing it 10 plus. I mean, Matt,
you've done this forever. The thing is
we made thousands and thousands of
mistakes. I love how Matt just our mic
just breached through. I was paying
three leases at the same time
and like joking about it, but at the
time you're like, "What in the we're
throwing money away, right? This is
crazy." The first one I chose because
they showed me a big empty warehouse and
said, "Look, we can move your stuff in
here and we can do it efficiently." And
I'm like, "Wow." Rather than the
basement of my current building, that
sounded like a really, really cool
thing. Then when they failed, we went to
a bigger, shinier building.
that promised better technology and
better service. And the people
seem to know what they were talking
about a lot better.
After several years, it came down to a
price. As we've scaled bigger and bigger
and bigger, we need the technology to
work with Shopify seamlessly and make
sure our inventory counts are right. The
sinking problems will kill you if you
have thousands of things and they
haven't moved it in the right thing or
if we have a big sale. We'll sell 20,000
bags in eight minutes sometimes. We'll
do something called the C-grade sale.
That's a lot. And if it's not updating
every couple seconds, you could oversell
five and 10,000 bags. And that is a
months and nightmares and and million
dollar problem that you have. So, it's
the technology.
It's do the executives seem to know what
they're talking about. So, they all have
transition teams. You're going to always
talk to a salesperson. Salesmen, they're
idiots. They don't know what they're
talking about, right? Yeah. They they
convince you that you should go with
them. But you have to talk to the
transition team before you sign the
contract. How would you do this? What is
the time? And you have to judge their
integrity as a person,
not as a what answers they're giving
you. It's do I really feel they've done
this for 10 years? Do I trust that if
there's a problem, I can talk to this
person? Is there something about this
person that I connect with? Because a
company is people. And people for you
are the people you can call up or you
can email and say, "This is a problem.
Can you help out with this?" in this
recent one in working with Flexport.
First of all, I met the press. I met the
the founder and he we can do it. The
next thing is we talked to their chief
financial officer. Then we went right
down the line, talked to 20 different
people. They assured us they can do it.
And I'm going to tell you right now,
when there's a problem, I call up the
scale and within a half hour something
is happening and getting taken care of.
Now, for all these people who are
listening to this, they're not able to
do that right away.
Here's my suggestion. Go with the two or
three people that you're talking to that
are not salespeople who will be somewhat
involved in your account. They have to
be involved in your account, not just,
oh, I set you up here and I moved out
because they'll all give you the stupid
tour. They'll all take you around and
say, look, we use robots and this little
robot will put the thing down and
everything. But yeah,
if you're scaling an e-commerce brand
today, ads alone aren't enough. After
focuses on the one moment that every
brand already owns after checkout and
turns the post-purchase moment into more
profit. Monetize every order with
post-purchase offers and thank you page
experiences without disrupting checkout
or hurting conversion. Enterprisegrade
tech used by Gap, Ticketmaster, Macy's,
and Target. Now driving results for
brands like True Classic, Hexclad,
Ridge, and Jones Road. I would know.
This is the reason I ended up buying
three pans from Hexcloud instead of two.
After generated over 1 billion in
additional revenue for e-commerce
brands, revenue that doesn't require
more traffic or higher CAC. So check out
Afterell and tell them that the operator
sent you.
It's funny that you're both going to
people like both you and Mike are
talking like the Mike more from a you
know man hiring and managing that type
of labor force. I'm happy you said it,
Mike. Like, nobody wants to say it, but
it is true. Like, it's it's a very
different animal from hiring like a head
of growth or or a CMO or, you know, a
CFO, like all that stuff,
>> right? Listen, when you're an
entrepreneur, part of the reason you're
an entrepreneur is that you get to
choose.
You get to choose. You get to choose the
problems you work on. You get to choose
the people that you work with. And that
that's why we do this, right? Everybody
goes to work and you get paid to solve
problems. That's what you do.
Entrepreneurs say, "I want to have
agency on what I work on, how much
upside I have, and who I work with." And
so, like, it's not rude to say that you
should make decisions around who do you
want to work with because it largely
influences the problems that you're
going to solve, which is the other big
thing. And so, like, that's what
entrepreneurship really is. I don't
think I've ever heard it described that
way, but that's what it really is. And I
think that that's my own personal
philosophy is that I want to have high
agency where I work on the type of
problems I want to work on with the type
of people I want to work with. And there
is nothing wrong with that. That's what
every single person is doing.
>> Yeah, I couldn't agree more. And I think
yes, I I'll just leave it at that. Yes.
100% yes. And you're both coming at the
same the same topic from two different
angles, right? Curtis, it's like, how do
I evaluate these companies? People
first. Mike, do I even want to do this?
People first, like, do I want to own
this? Um, then I think Curtis, you hit
on another point, which is uh you you
you talked about it in the frame of
technology. So, like, do they have the
systems to handle us? But what you're
really getting at, what you mentioned is
like right underneath that is inventory
accounts need to be accurate. This can
screw up my financials. It has like
meaningful balance sheet impact. It can
have tax impact. All that stuff actually
needs to be really dialed. That's like
one way to evaluate, right? It's like
how tight are you operationally as a
3PL. I think the other one, Curtis, um,
and I don't know if you guys do this,
but are you going sort of single node or
multi-node, right? So, like when you're
evaluating a 3PL and the size of your
business, like are you shipping out of
one location? Are you shipping out of
multiple? That has an inventory impact.
So, there it this thing gets real
complicated real quick, right?
So yes. Okay. Single node. Oh, first of
all, Mike, again, people say, "Why are
you on this podcast?" Like, "Why do you
get up and do this podcast?" It's to
listen to Mike tell me informative
like that because I'm like, "Wait, I
thought I sounded smart." But he brought
it down to, "Yes, I get to choose the
people I want to work with. That is what
life is about."
>> High agency people charge each other up.
Paul Graham has a great line about this.
He's like, "You can't actually see
ambition fully when people are young
because they haven't been able to self-
select into groups of other ambitious
people. But when you put ambitious
people around other ambitious people,
it's like a wilted plant that all of a
sudden is getting water. It just like
perks up." And like it I'm the same way.
Like the reason why I love doing it is
the same exact reason that you love
doing it, Curtis. that when we are
around each other like it just fires me
up and it just re it like makes me want
to be that version of myself that's the
really high agency version and I think
that this is like the power of the
internet really is that like 200 years
ago I would have just had to make do
with whoever was around me that was
close enough and now I can get Crazy
Curtis in Portland you know and Matt in
Canada and I get the and so like I'm
Amen. I'm I'm right there with you.
I'm gonna go to that single node
multi-node.
>> Yeah, tell tell me about that because I
think that's an important one for people
to hear. Um, I'll give you some context.
What made me think of it is I think
about two years ago, Mike, I don't know
if you remember, but Jason from
Hexcloud, they did this huge analysis of
their business and they were basically
shipping everything out of like a single
node and then they ultimately went to I
think three across the country. All of
it based on like cost and margin, right?
like they're just they're at the size
where they had to do that. You're also
at a size with a lot of product. And I
don't know how I wanted to just hear how
you think about that part because that
ties into your whole like inventory
counts matter. Not just inventory
counts, but our we make in Mexico and we
send right across the border and we go
to Dallas. Okay. So, ironically, our
biggest market, which is Portland and
Seattle, get their packages the slowest.
So you and you're really and and hey,
let's talk. These are entrepreneurs.
Let's talk real people in Texas who do
their first buy who get it like within
48 hours, their LTV skyrockets over to
people who it takes four days to get it
to.
>> Yes. Yes. Absolutely. So we know for a
fact if we can get those first purchases
there much quicker, their LTV immediate,
their second purchase jumps immediately,
right? So then it's like, well, that
makes sense. Let's do this. Okay. The
average uh number of products that
someone buys from us is 1.68 per
purchase, right? So they're buying a bag
and they're getting a wallet or
something small along with it, right? So
they want all of those colors and so all
of our SKUs in like 8 9,000 have to be
in stock. And if we're trying to send
that all around,
we can't keep in stock in three
different locations. So, we have to get
to the north. California and the
Northwest and huge in the Northeast, New
York, uh Connecticut, Boston is huge for
us, right? So, we would have to have
several different nodes. We don't have
the product to fill that at this point.
>> Oh, yeah. So, it is it's genuinely like
how the hell do I inventory? Because if
you do multi-node, it's like you need
everything everywhere all at once. If
that's how if you're truly going to do
it, you know, like this is this goes
back to the like when I saw the Amazon
news that they're basically going to
open up their network now in an AWS way.
I'm like I I've never I've never really
had a strong opinion on like speed, how
much speed matters outside of an Amazon.
Like when I'm buying toilet paper, it's
like, oh my god, I need toilet paper
now, right? But if I'm buying a purse,
it's like, can I wait two weeks? You
know, like do I really care? And you
saying that that matters makes me think
this is where an Amazon genuinely has an
advantage because their fulfillment
infrastructure is just like it's clearly
the best. Like there's no question it's
the best. Um it's what they do. Um Mike,
are you guys
when you think about like building out
your own facility or or bringing it back
in house, would you do that in one
location? Would you do that multi? cuz
you're also incredibly omni channel and
I think that's a variable here is like
are you fulfilling largely consumer are
you fulfilling largely retail like those
are very different packouts those are
very different fulfillment lines like
can you break that down for me a bit
>> there's a lot of nuance here I'll just
give a few kind of highle principles I
think the number of skus you have really
dictates whether multi-node really makes
any sense and like we have 5,000 SKs
with simple modern and when we went to
multi-node the biggest thing we learned
was that for any savings, for any
benefits, you introduce five new
problems. Uh where it's like, hey, why
is this not live on the website? Oh,
well, it's active here but not here. And
uh hey, why did we overorder this? Oh,
well, we forgot we had 10,000 units of
it, you know, in in Ununice. They they
were receiving it and it wasn't yet in
our system for some reason. And so I
just think that in general if you have a
single skew and you're at insane scale,
okay, maybe multiple um locations like
in in the United States, now obviously
international is a different thing, but
if you have a bunch of different SKUs,
if you're really rapidly growing, it
kind of comes back to the same principle
that like there is plenty of complexity
that already exists. do not introduce
more complexity in your business unless
there's a very clear path to why that is
an amplifier for your business. And so
we've actually kind of collapsed down
towards a more centralized we're doing
almost everything kind of in Oklahoma at
this point. And there's some some cool
opportunities that are only possible
that way. So, like we we got on a
program with Walmart where they just
pick up entire pallets. Instead of them
giving us purchase orders where it's a
certain number of units and you kind of
have to compile it or whatever, you just
are like, "Hey, you can order in
pallets." And they just come up and and
they the truck pulls up and then you get
the forklift and you just drop the the
pallet on their truck. And so like the
efficiency is like through the roof. So,
uh we've collapsed down to one. I've
seen use cases like I think Hexcloud has
multiple nodes and they did a big uh
analysis on it and it was worth millions
of dollars for them. So it's definitely
possible if you get really big that and
you're doing a lot of individual
fulfillment where multiple nodes can
make sense. I just think that you have
to have some pretty extreme scale and
you have to have a more narrow skew band
to really make it work. Otherwise, it's
just unnecessary uh complexity that
you're adding to your business.
Call me a nerd if you want, but one of
my favorite things is when one of my
existing software partners, in this
case, Northbeam, adds something that I
would have had to have normally paid
more and separately for. Incrementality
was broken and Northbeam decided to fix
it.
>> Matt, you're not just a nerd, you're
also cheap. Yeah. And one of the things
my team and I are looking forward to
with this is now having MTA and
incrementality cleanly tied together.
It's really nice having multiple views
of a test totally integrated from design
to monitoring. We can just focus on the
insights and not the logistics. So now
your incrementality test results, they
just feed right into your Northbeam MTA
dashboards that we're just used to
looking at every day. Yeah, I don't
think any of us are going to say no to
less work and making life easier for all
of our teams. Uh if this is interesting
to you, go to northbeam.io and ask for a
demo and feel free to tell them that the
operator sent you.
We've been talking about like 3PL's, how
do you evaluate them? We've mentioned a
couple things that would drive you guys
bringing it inhouse, right? So, like
growth rate is a really interesting
starting point. Um, Chiron, we'll drop a
link to his post on X because he he
jumped into this conversation, right?
Shiron being the the CEO of Fulfill,
who's one of our sponsors. One of the
reasons I actually like Fulfill as a
sponsor is Shrew is freaking smart,
works his ass off, and he just like
culturally they're killer team. But his
he put together like this list of and
I'm going to just rifle them off for you
because I want to get your take on this.
Um this list of like when would owning
your own fulfillment make sense, right?
And he talks about manufacturing,
Curtis. So like if you already
manufacture, the last step of just
shipping it is easier. Mike and Curtis,
the retail store thing is another
variable he threw in. Like if you own a
lot of your own stores or you're having
to do that kind of fulfillment, 3PL's
kind of suck at cross docking and they
kind of suck at like DTOC 3PLs typically
don't do B2B 3PL work very well. Uh at
least in my experience that's true. So
that's another thing for people to
consider. The third one is you
personalize almost every order. I know
if Katie was here she'd be screaming at
us saying like that she owns her own
fulfillment and she does like I think 30
or 40% of her business is personalized.
Um, but she just ran into your problem,
Curtis, which is she had to double the
size of her facility and so she's now
working on that issue. Uh, the fourth is
apparel. We hit on this, which is skew
counts get into the thousands. So, like
that's a thing. Here's a fun one. Never
thought of this. Hazmat. So, like if you
sell anything with aerosols or alcohol
or lithium batteries, like these are
very specific requirements. I didn't
even consider that. uh anything over 50
pounds, furniture, fitness equipment, uh
that kind of stuff. He's like that
actually might be better if you own the
dock, you own the LTL relationships, the
lift gates, like all that Um, and
then frozen food, guys. I didn't even
consider this, but you know, how many
people listen to this show are in CPG in
some way, uh, might have like very
unique product requirements that again,
there's not a lot of 3PL options. I
don't know if if you have any others
that you would add to this list, but
when I was looking at Chiron's list and
I was looking at Pila, uh I'm like,
okay, so like we manufacture, we do
retail, we we do personalization, we
have a crazy ass skew count. I don't
think our products have a hazmat
problem. Uh they definitely don't weigh
50 pounds and they're not frozen. But I
checked a lot of these boxes,
right? And Curtis, you check a lot of
these boxes. I'm glad that I didn't
think all these things through before I
started my business or I never would
have been an entrepreneur. This stuff
sucks and I don't know how I get through
it and still stay so optimistic. Uh we
actually use uh a great 3PL but we try
to cut some of this out because we
manufacture in Mexico and we have an
enormous enormous what we call a SETI
central distribution unit. They're in a
system in Mexico. We are now shipping
directly to our retail stores from
Mexico manufacturing. So, we're not we
cut out the cross stockcking of them.
So, they can now get the orders. It's
all put together and goes directly from
Mexico right to the retail stores
because that became a problem of making
sure that they had the right things. So,
that was one of the solves that we did
on that. Um,
too many things can go wrong on that.
I've seen those cooling units and like
having to deal with like beverages and
cold and meats and all of that. That's
just an entire huge industry. We're
lucky enough to stay away. Katie Mamari
is amazing that she does all this plus
the personalization. Like I I just it's
it's staggering. But again for
entrepreneurs, I'm an entrepreneur at
everything inside of me. I prefer growth
than all of the little things you have
to do. So I looked at yesterday, I'm in
here in Portland and we met and we said,
"Hey, I think we can add 40 million more
this year onto our revenue." Right? I
really believe that from what we thought
we were going to do, we can add 40
million more. So, I want to
do the marketing rather than deal with
all this crap that we do in the 3PL.
Mike, Mike knows about some of this.
Mike, what do you got?
>> I I think you're alluding to a really
good point with personalization stuff,
and that's something I didn't really
touch on, and it's one of the best
arguments for running a physical space
is that you're able to do something
differentiated and create some kind of
competitive advantage with it. And when
you can do that, you should absolutely
think about doing that. So for us, one
of our big value ads, uh, our kids
business is just crushing it. It just,
it's actually kind of shocking because
our kids business is kind of like this
aspect of our business that we focus
more on adult and kids just keeps
growing faster than adult no matter what
we [laughter] do. It's kind of like the
market's just like, we want more of your
kids stuff. But one of our things like
back to school uh, has been huge for us.
It's our best kind of DTOC window. And
the reason is because the carts are
really big and because embroidery and
laser engraving is huge. I mean, if
you've had kids, they lose stuff all the
time and they they'll have a water
bottle that looks the way that, you
know, 15 other kids at their school's
water bottle does. And so actually like
basically putting their name on stuff
has a huge value ad in a number of
different ways. And and it looks good.
And so like we've we've got several
embroidery machines. We have probably
20some lasers and this is a huge part of
actually why we're doing our own
facility. [clears throat] We have um a
period like with back to school and we
generally kind of personalize stuff
throughout the year. And then we have a
really good custom business that's uh
kind of high seven figures, low eight
figures of custom orders that we do for
corporate partners and and different
people that are just wanting to order,
you know, 50 or 500 tumblers or whatever
for something. And that's a great
business to be in. Um, and it's another
example where having centralized
inventory and and stuff can can really
pay off. So I I would say like we're
we're kind of coming back to a thing
over and over again, which is you
shouldn't do this just to do it. You
shouldn't do it if it's adding
complexity when you don't need to add
complexity. But there are certain
situations where your product demands it
or where you can build a competitive
advantage off of being willing to work
in the physical world. And then I would
heavily endorse it because e-commerce is
so competitive and it's so easy for
somebody to put out your exact same
offer, competing offer. You've got to be
looking for surface area where I can
offer something that other people can't
or won't.
>> Yeah, I think that that's the that's
actually a really good point, Mike. Uh
and Curtis, I suspect at some point
you're going to hit this where
the growth rate slows,
right? And you're going to start to look
at like, okay, well, where else can we
actually build moat and build like be
very different?
>> I'm not making this up. I'm not
exaggerating. We started our first years
on Etsy where we personalize. So, we'd
get an order, we'd hand write it, and we
would pass it along and we would make
every piece for that person. And then we
got too good for that and we moved on
and said to scale, we can't do that.
Mike has just recently I have never
thought of bringing personalization back
until Mike just talked and I'm like oh
that's a really good idea
>> and you guys would crush at it at your
scale you would it's
>> you would kill bringing that back
>> but it but it even even something like
personalization it just requires scale
for it to make sense like we and we've
run into this like early on it's like oh
we got to have personalization and it's
like okay it's on we're doing 50 units a
day or 30 units a day and it's like ah
it's hard for that to be worth it you
need hundreds of units a day but when
you do get to a certain and this is the
order of operations thing like Curtis in
your business I don't know your business
the way that you do there is a
definitely a scale where personalization
makes sense and then that's the order of
operations thing of just kind of like
deciding when are we at the scale where
this is the right move for us
>> it's so like now I'm listening to you
Curtis here and I I the second thing I
wanted to actually talk about today is
this idea of like the founder
reinvention cycle. And what you're
hitting on here, Curtis, is like a
perfect example. Okay. You you didn't
even think about like layering back in
personalization.
And the reason I'm tying this in is
because like it takes it's such a
different animal to run a company where
like all you are is a marketing company,
which is what you've kind of been
talking about, Curtis. And I know Sean
talks about this. Like I look at it like
everything I do is marketing first. And
when you start to run your own logistics
or your own manufacturing, like this is
now a very different company, you know,
and I think Mike, you're hitting on this
too. And that are you the right CEO to
do that? Are you the right guy? Like or
can you get the right people? And
there's this constant like reinvention
thing that happens. And Curtis, you've
been a big advocate for talking about
this in the show, but like this past
couple weeks, you've seen Tim Cook is
stepping down, Doug McMillan from
Walmart is stepping down. You got a lot
of CEOs putting their hands up saying
like I think this next generation of the
company needs a different kind of leader
and a different kind of leadership. I
when I see this I inevitably go to uh is
this possible at companies our size?
Like can you do this at this scale or is
the founder founder mode founder juice
just too damn too damn valuable still?
Yes, it's too damn valuable. But you
know, you you guys are young whippers
snappers, okay? You guys are just these
young folks doing this stuff. And I've,
you know, I'm ease into that a little
bit later years. And some things just
I'm going to be honest. I'm very
flexible. My mind does things.
I
have thought that maybe somebody
becoming CEO would be a better thing for
the scale that we're going to.
>> And every time I do that, it takes me
about a night to go home and then
egotistically think, "No, they can't do
what I can do. They don't got the
energy. They don't got this. They don't
got this." And there's some amazing
people. Uh Maverick said something to me
one time. He said, "Curtis, could the
best CEO in the world take our company
from 250 million to 500 million?" I'm
like, "The best one? Well, sure. The
best one could do that, right?" So, then
it's just a degree from me to that
person. Can we find someone who could do
that better than me in certain ways? And
I think that it's probably possible. Uh,
of course, they're not going to have my
energy. Uh, but my energy creates
problems too, right? Mike's always
saying these wise things about order of
things. I'm just like, hit that
really, really hard and most of it works
out. And if it doesn't work out, I just
say I meant to do it that way and I keep
moving. Right. So, I believe that there
is a and I believe that there's new
technology coming that is going to take
new minds in order to to do it. Uh, I I
really do. I don't think I'm going into
AI hard enough. I'm not going into
certain technologies. I'm not writing
some of this as fast as I I think I've
got years. I don't got a decade.
[snorts]
Every SAS company says they are AI
powered, but very few can explain what
it actually does for the revenue of my
brand. This is why Postcript's approach
stood out to us. They don't just build
AI for demos or buzzwords. They built it
to drive real incremental revenue.
Postcripts AI called Shopper. shows up
inside of SMS at moments with real buyer
intent when shoppers are likely asking
questions, hesitating, maybe even about
to drop off. Shopper can answer product
questions instantly, answer questions
about fit, availability,
recommendations, order issues, the kinds
of stuff that people usually bounce for.
This means more conversions, higher AOV,
less loss demand. So you are driving
more revenue and doing it more
efficiently. Check out Shopper from
Postcript. We use it at Pilo, which is
why I am telling you to check it out.
Mike, uh, I think we've talked about
that we've danced around this topic in
past episodes, but there is a certain
element of what Curtis is saying, which
is like the job of the founder sometimes
is to inject risk into a company and
like at a certain stage it's like that
you should be injecting risk into a
company and then at some point it
changes, right? And that like companies
maybe are wanting less risk, less
founder energy, uh, and a little more
stability. Simple Modern uh as a company
is like this massive omni channel
machine.
You know, this whole like Curtis view of
do you you have to reinvent the company
every year like how do you think about
this at Simple Modern and how are you
thinking about like long-term sort of
succession and your role and all I mean
I guess all of it when it comes to this
type of thing.
>> Yeah. Well, I'm Curtis and and I and and
really this is true of several of the
people we've had on the pod.
It is very rare to found a brand and
then to CEO it from zero to hundreds of
millions. And the reason for that is
that it just is very different at the
different stages what it requires to be
an effective and successful leader. And
it takes, I would say, a pretty
tremendous amount of neuroplasticity
to be able to continue to grow and be
willing to make the changes that it
requires from you as a leader. And one
of the observations I've made is that so
like when you're 0 to 10 million, let's
say, like you're the quarterback and
you've got to be great at throwing
touchdown passes and reading the defense
and like that's your job. And if you're
not doing it, you're not scoring. And so
then you get to like say 10 to 30
million and it's like, hey, I I've got
to add people to my team or like I
cannot like do everything right now, but
I still got to be like throwing
touchdown passes, but I also have to
kind of simultaneously be be like
coaching the offensive line on what
they're doing and like telling the
running back, hey, you need to be lined
up here or whatever. And then you get to
like 30 to 60, 30 to 75 million and it
starts to be like, hey, I actually need
some of these players that I've hired. I
need them to start doing some of the the
kind of directing people and I need to
start, you know, doing less and less
executing and thinking a little bit, you
know, abstracting up and being a little
bit more of like a coach role. So maybe
you're a player coach. And then there's
a point where it's like, hey, this
thing's getting big enough where it's
like you need to kind of just
exclusively coach. And these are all
transitions that are like I mean how
many times have we seen somebody who was
a great sports player who tries to be a
sports owner and totally fails at it.
It's just like it's totally different
muscle set. It's totally different skill
set. Michael Jordan, greatest basketball
player of all time, terrible basketball
owner because it's a different skill
set. And I think that entrepreneurship
is the exact same way that you you've
got to wear all these different hats as
the company continues to grow. And it's
like are you willing to like make those
transitions?
And if you're not careful, what happens
is you'll develop elite skill sets at
certain stages. Like I have these elite
skill sets as a individual contributor.
I I use this example for me like I'm
great in a spreadsheet, right? I'll put
myself in a spreadsheet up against
almost anybody, very fast, very
effective, very good with data.
And so obviously in the very early days
of Simple Modern, it was like huge
asset, right? I'm running an e-commerce
business and that's a huge asset. And
then as we started to get a little bit
bigger, it was like, well, it's still
probably an asset, but sometimes I kind
of feel like it's taking me away from
talking to people or doing other things
that I should be doing. And then around
the time that we hit about 100 million
in revenue, I realized if I am in a
spreadsheet during time that I'm in the
office, like it's just a fail, right?
I'm not doing my job very well. But that
muscle is so developed and I'm so good
at that that it's like when I get
stressed, when I don't know what to do,
you know what my first like my binky is?
my binky is Excel. I want to pull up
Excel and it's like that's how I'm going
to fix things. And it's just like that's
not how it works. And so, ironically,
the better you are at something, the
more that that thing can then sabotage
you as a company grows. And so, like,
I've seen that risk with me and it's
very difficult to work against that. A
lot of times people will just say, "Hey,
I'm awesome at this. I want to keep
doing this." And so, I'll go just start
another company or I'll let you know,
like whatever. So, I think that's one
thing. And then I think the other thing
that that is probably going on here is
that there is something that has to do
with what generation did you grow up in
and what were the experiences you had in
your life and your ability to lead or
manage a company is kind of prisoner to
those things. So it would be very
difficult for somebody who let's say was
born in the 60s to really
lead a company into the mobile
revolution uh effectively, right? U it's
not to say that some people didn't. It
just would be hard because you grew up
without mobile technology and so you
don't think natively in that way like a
20 year as somebody that had grown up in
the you know whatever that was born in
2000 and grew up in the 2010s their
understanding of technology and mobile
phones and how they intersect with life
and culture is like totally different
than somebody born 20 or 30 years
earlier. And so you do kind of age out
in some ways. Like maybe Walmart's not a
good example of that, but especially
when you're in e-commerce, when you're
in technology, I do think there is
something about like it's a young man's
game because it's difficult to think AI
native or to think, you know, mobile
native when that wasn't a part of your
experience growing up. You know, Mike, I
think what's interesting, you're both
saying similar things here, but uh what
the CEO transitions we are seeing at
this scale, they are actually pointing
to like we're heading into a different
world. Like this is a different time and
and companies are going to run in a
different way. Um you know, and these
guys are are seasoned, you know,
seasoned experts. So like they're
putting their hands up and saying like
this is my thing. It's time for me to
go. Uh or this is my moment. It's time
for me to go. Curtis, do you like Mike
talked about his binky as like the
spreadsheet? Do you have a a thing that
you're like, I'm exceptionally good at
this. I always go back to this one
thing. This is where I spend my time.
Yes. Uh, and it's not spreadsheets. Um,
my ability is to memorize
the numbers outside of the spreadsheet
and have my brain work on unique
situations and my subconscious uh while
I'm just walking through the world. I
tell everybody if I ask somebody a
question like what is that number and
they have to look at their computer and
I'm like stop. Like that's an easy
number. You have to have that in your
head. Why? I'm very good at putting this
in my head and then as I walk through
our facility, we're in meetings, I'm in
calls, I'm at the store, I'm in the car,
my brain is working on solutions because
I have the numbers and it's moving it
around in a new way. So when someone
shows me a spreadsheet, I can show them
new ways to look at that that they can't
see from put in this number and build it
to this number. I actually can say no,
no, no, no. I know that that's what the
numbers say, but it's wrong. We have to
do a system completely different. Have
we thought about this, this, and this?
It's looking from a completely different
angle than everybody who's looking at
their computer. That's I just like I'm
like, turn off your computer. Put it
down. Stop. Do you know the numbers in
your head? Let's talk about this. Let's
figure it out in our minds and let our
minds spend days on coming up with
something unique because that computer's
going to tell us the same damn thing
every single time. and everybody's
staring at the computer. What about what
of us that's unique that we can bring to
this situation?
>> You know, I I I would say mine is
probably performance marketing. Like I
go if I'm like I'm bored or I don't know
what to do and I don't feel productive,
I'll I'll start writing copy. I'll start
looking at ad accounts. I'll like I'll
go after creative and I'm thinking of
angles for a product. I it is such a
muscle that I can't even help doing it
with my friends. Like I was hanging out
with my buddy who's got a company and
he's telling me about his business and
I'm like have you thought about this?
Have you thought about this? Have you
thought like I immediately it's the most
overdeveloped muscle I have as a as a
founder. So like it's so easy to go over
there. Uh Mike, I'm like you like that's
my like if I feel uncomfortable with the
silence I'll start working on those
things. Um but I think it's a it's
actually like it makes me think uh like
when we talked to Tim from Eucalyptus,
right? he had this, you know, you should
hire away from you as a skill set, away
from your core skill set. I thought that
was such a good take. I I think that one
additional thing I'll layer on here. I
think that anytime a really gifted
founder totally extracts from a
business, I think the business does
worse. I think your business will always
be better if you're involved in some
capacity. I think the wisdom is figuring
out how do I inject the thing that only
I can inject and then you know hire and
build up those abilities other places
there. Nobody in my organization is
going to be able to give the risk-on
nature, the let's freaking go, the uh
the ambition, the vision that I'm going
to. Uh and part of that is also like I'm
the biggest shareholder. So like it's
more my money than anybody else. So how
can I expect anybody else to be as
riskone as I am? That's it's an
unrealistic expectation. So even if I
someday abstract out of the CEO role, I
have to find a way to continue to inject
in the organization the thing that I can
only bring at the level that I can can
bring it. The one other thing I it's my
one of my favorite sayings of all time,
but it goes back to this binky idea.
When you're a hammer, everything looks
like a nail. And it's just like such a
great self assessment is how are you
like a hammer? like what are the things
where you like you always want to solve
it in the same way or you always want to
apply the same lens to to things and
it's it's a great like self-reflection
exercise to kind of find out where you
are less effective than you could be
because you just always generalize back
to it's more marketing more creative
more Excel more whatever and uh like
it's how you I think this is the way
that you make breakthroughs as a leader
and it's the reason why being a truly
great leader is hard because it requires
a lot of internal reflection and a lot
of willingness to change and that
requires a level of security and who you
are that few people get to. But if you
don't if you don't do it, if you allow
your insecurity, because basically what
we'll do is like growth requires looking
backwards and saying, "Okay, I can see
now I was not as good a leader as I
wanted to be because I constantly tried
to find the answer and excel." And a lot
of people when you're insecure, it's
like you can't deal with that idea. It
it invalidates you to a level of like
you've done things wrong in the past
that you just can't accept it and so you
just ignore it. you know, this is really
effective leaders are like, "That's
fine. I could have been better. I see it
and now I'm going to try and be better
tomorrow and I'll probably still
struggle with it, but I now see it and
I'm going to I'm going to choose to to
kind of grow in that area."
What's up operators? Welcome to the Rich
Panel ad read. Rich Panel has been a
sponsor for over 12 months. I've been a
paying customer for over 12 months. And
guess what? I just renewed to pay again
for another year. We have cut our SAS
bill in half and automation dropped our
cost per ticket by 70%. Our seesat has
also improved from 88% which is still
really good to 96% best-in-class all
powered by rich panel. I told them last
year, hey, you guys need to do the same
thing with returns. And now Rich Panel
has a returns portal. It's built to cut
down your tickets and convert more
refunds into exchanges. They do the
heavy lifting, data import,
self-service, retention flows, team
training, all of it, and it'll be live
in two weeks. If you want to save 30%
guaranteed on help desk and now returns,
book a demo.
I guess I could probably argue the other
side of that
as a founder, right? I think what you're
hitting on is like as a CEO, you've got
a lot of other jobs that are probably
just that one area that you can be like
a great individual contributor, but then
as a founder, I could argue that if
you're a great hammer, you should go
look for more nails, right? Like that
just personal leverage.
>> Maybe. I mean, maybe like I I love I
love a little conflict here because it's
like, listen, it depends on what you're
what skill set you're talking about. If
you're like, I'm an amazing gatherer of
talent and I'm just going to be, you
know, that's how I'm going to try and
solve every problem is gather more
talent, maybe that works out. I still I
I don't know. May maybe if if that's
your So, there's certain skills where if
you just said, hey, I don't have to do
anything more than just be elite at this
one thing. But I generally have found
that life is not so simple. Uh the other
here's the other problem with that Matt.
It will maybe work in one area of your
life, but it won't generalize to all the
areas of your life which will prevent
you from being successful. So right,
have you ever have you ever tried to in
your marriage tried to use the same, you
know, like you you see nail you see
nails in your marriage and you try and
be the hammer and you tell me how that
works out for you. So I I I think being
successful in life requires like
adaptability and flexibility.
And uh maybe maybe in business you can
kind of say, "Hey, here's my elite skill
set and I'm just only going to focus on
that thing." But generally like the most
successful people are successful because
they have a diversity of really elite
skill sets and then they kind of know
when to pull the right tool out of their
tool belt.
>> Curtis, what say you on this?
>> You know, Tim Cook's leaving because he
was around a long time. I'm just
starting to get good at this after
10 years, right? Like I had a bunch of
drinking in the middle of my life that
stalled my life out for a while or I
might have got better earlier on, but at
10 years, Mike's at 11 years, you're at
10 plus. Like, we're all just starting
to get good at it. Tim Cook did this
thing for 30, right? I think things have
moved past him a little bit. He was
great at logistics. He was the COO. I
get that. I think that I'm We started
from the ground. Tim Cook entered a big
company and learned how to do it. Mike
built the damn thing. He was meeting
upstairs at his house. You built this,
Matt. You know, Sean built Ridge at past
4 million. Like, we all built this
thing. And it takes a while to get good
at it. And now that we're good, we don't
want to step all the way. There's still
a lot of growth that I need to learn
about. I need to learn better about
people. I need to learn better about
3PL's. I need to learn better
technology. I need to continue to hire.
I need to get all this So 10 years
is just like when you grow, I'm just
like Tom Brady. Hey, in mid-30s, he was
just learning the game. He was just
getting really good at figuring exactly
what it is and getting better and
better. Now, physically, he was going to
age a little bit. We're not going to age
that much. We're going to be fine. We're
smart enough. We got the energy. So, we
can keep doing this. And I think that
if it's not just this company for me,
it's multiple companies. And I think it
is for Mike and man, I think it is for
you. Like now that I got this knowledge,
I can look at other companies. I can't
help it. I was at dinner last night
talking to people and I'm just like,
talk to me about what you're going no no
no. And I could just see it. I could see
the pattern recognition of what they
were not doing and what they needed to
do. So I think it's multiple companies,
not just one big company. Well, really
talented people get bored is what you're
saying, Curtis. Like I might be the best
pattern recognition ever at a particular
thing, but that doesn't mean that's what
I want to do for the next 30 years. It's
like I want to I want to take on new
problems and I want to expand my skill
set. And I think this is what's true of
ambitious people. Like I don't want
there was a great quote that I posted
yesterday which is like my ambition in
life is to be defeated by greater and
greater challenges. This is what growth
mindset and ambition looks like. And so
like this is the other problem with what
you kind of espouseed Matt. It's just
like, man, it'd be such a depressing
idea to me if my tool belt and my
ability to solve problems is the exact
same 20 years from now that it is today.
Like, I hope it's so much more diverse.
I hope I'm able to take on so many more
different things. I hope that there's
problems that I'm going to take on and
help people solve that I have no idea
how to solve today. I think this is what
makes business so interesting is it's
like this infinite game where it
supplies interesting things for us to
work on and build on, you know, for the
rest of our lives, which I love.
>> Yeah. I I I don't disagree with you,
Mike. Uh I'm thinking of it more
>> I'm manufacturing drama here, Matt,
because you and I never here's here's
the here's the thing, right? I raise it
because uh I think what you're what
you're both hitting on is um there is
like ambitious entrepreneurs and that is
a certain kind of person, right? There
is also ambitious and driven non-
entrepreneurs and I would put Tim Cook
in that bucket where like he is the
all-time greatest CEO if you just look
at the numbers. Like yes, he came into a
big company but he came into a big
company that was worth $400 million and
he's leaving one worth4 trillion. Like
that is an incredible amount of economic
value created as a driven like
operations guy, you know, like that's
exactly what that company needed. So
like he was basically like I have a very
specific skill set. Uh and he took it to
the very top of business, which is what
made me argue the like maybe you just
need a different nail, right? It's like
you're so damn good at this like you're
just in the wrong boat. Um, so I I guess
that was my my push back is in Tim
Cook's wear, his perspective, he did
just hammer a damn nail his whole life.
He just did it in the right boat. Uh,
and that boat got real big. Um,
>> you're not supposed to hammer nails into
boats, buddy. I'm just letting
[laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah. Sorry.
Thanks for screwing up the analogy,
Chris. [laughter]
>> Let's bring it right back around to
where we started. And I want to finish
on the 3PL topic and let's play a little
game. Okay, we're gonna we're going to
call this red flag, green flag, and I
want each of you to give me uh I'm gonna
I'm gonna basically call you out,
Curtis. I'm gonna start with you. What
is a green flag
that you are looking for when evaluating
A3PL?
>> No, I want to start with the red flag.
>> Okay, you start with red. Let's let's
let Mike let's let Mike do green. I like
Okay. Flexibility. flexibility and a
willingness to grow with your business
and to to modify their plans based on
your business's changing needs.
>> Okay, Curtis, red flag.
>> They're gonna say that the red flag is
when you go and see this big warehouse
and they're showing you how fancy and
how they can build your racking and do
everything. If the people you're talking
to are number one salespeople or they're
the manager is new and they're bringing
like the regional manager who says, "Oh,
I spend a lot of time here, but they
flew him in from Tahoe to show you." It
means no one onsite knows what the hell
they're doing. It's new and there's no
manager running it. And yes, those are
specific examples that happened to me.
Okay, Mike, do you have a red flag? What
would you what would cause you to look
the other way? bad systems. Bad systems.
It like it the worst thing in the world
is when you have a 3PL and you cannot
understand what the heck is going on. Uh
like and we we grew with a 3PL, but like
there was an example that we had this
print no ship where they would print out
labels and we thought that that meant it
had shipped, but that didn't. It just
meant that the label had been printed.
And so we had a whole nightmare around
trying to communicate with customers and
not knowing what had actually shipped
versus just what label had been printed.
So, I think systems is a huge red flag
if they're not advanced in systems,
especially in this day and age.
>> I'll throw in a red flag. I think if the
3PL's been around for 10 or 20 years and
they don't have any customers that have
been with them that long, I would also
be concerned.
>> Yeah, references. Lack of references.
Red flag.
>> Yeah. Curtis, green or red? What do you
want?
>> I I'm going to go back to a green. Uh,
>> look at you being positive.
>> I know. Well, let's I want to I want to
do that, but 3PL's you just like, you
know, I I want them to work better than
they do. But yeah, here is what it is
that they don't just promise the
technology. They let you when you're
talking to them, talk to some of the
technology people and they'll start
walking you through for an hour or two
like this is what we use. This is the
integration, this is how we do it. And
they give you examples of things that
went wrong in the past, not just
everything's easy. They're like, "Yes,
we've had this problem before and it
created this. This can be a problem."
They start telling you about problems
that can occur. Not like, "Oh, we're so
good at this. It's easy. We got We got a
tech guy in Lexington and this guy can
do anything." Nobody in Lex can do.
>> Mike, what do you want? Green or red?
Uh, I'll give a red. A red is they have
lots of really big clients because be
careful. You're not gonna matter.
They're not gonna flex to you. Like
you're not gonna be meaningful to their
business. Oh, that's good. Yeah. You
don't want to be the very smallest
client. Um I'll give you a green flag.
Uh they work with other companies uh in
your space so they can kind of see how
your product category works. They know
all of the nuances of like what it is to
ship apparel or what it is to ship
frozen food or something like that.
>> I love that. I a lot of them always say,
"Oh, and they give you the big names of
people they work with." Well, it's Katy
Perry's new this or something like that.
And it's like, yeah, yeah, I want to
know more about a D TOC company that's
doing nine figures that has a bunch of
SKs that's a pain in the ass who's
always switching just like we are. And
how do you work with someone like us?
Because I'm D to C. I move fast. Boom,
boom, boom, boom, boom. They have to
move fast, too. This is an old system.
They've got to be updated for the way
things are done. And that means minutes
and hours, not days and weeks.
[music]